Guide to the Salwa Mikdadi Papers AD.MC.022
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Exhibitions, 1989-2009; 5.0 Linear Feet in 12 boxes.
  - Other exhibitions: not curated by Mikdadi
    - United States, Texas: Denton, University of North Texas, 2005 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - United States, Texas: Houston, "Made in Palestine", 2005 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Venice Biennale, 2009
    - Guides, general (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Guides: "Making Worlds" (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Artists biographies, 2009 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Artists statements, 2009 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Brochures and postcards, 2009 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Correspondence, 2007-2010 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Design and floor-plan, 2009 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Events, 2009 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Installations: Riwaq Biennale, 2009 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Installations: Stations (E. Jacir), 2009 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Planning: pocket diary, 2008-2009 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Press coverage, 2009-2010 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Palestinian pavilion: Visas, 2009 (Box 48, Folder 4)
- Other activities, 2009-2018; 0.8 Linear Feet in 2 boxes.
  - Emirates Foundation: Arts and Culture Program, 2009-2012
    - Activities summaries, 2010-2011 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Brochures and postcards (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Cite des Arts (Paris), 2011 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Events, 2009-2012 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Newsletters, 2010-2011 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Planning, 2011 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Press coverage, 2009 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Press coverage, 2010 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Press coverage, 2011 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Press coverage, 2012 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Press releases and publicity, 2010-2011 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Projects sponsored, 2009-2011 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Scholarships, 2009 (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - General, 2009-2019
    - Document 12 / Bruno Kreisky Forum, 1993-2007 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Press coverage, 2013-2017 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Press coverage, 2018-2019 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Sheikha Manal's Young Artist Award (Dubai), 2009 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Speaking engagements: Arab Press / Mori Museum (Japan), 2012 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Speaking engagements: Foto Fest (Houston, TX), 2014 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Speaking engagements: other, 2009-2012 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Other activities, miscellaneous, 2010-2018 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - New York University Abu Dhabi, 2010-2019 (Box 49, Folder 9)
- Video
  General
  Closed pending processing.
  - Artist interviews and documentary footage
    - Ali, Princess Wijdan: interview in Jordan, discussing the role Jordan National Gallery of Fine Arts and its holdings, undated, circa 1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0062)
    - Azzawi, Dia (ʻAzzāwī, Ḍiyāʼ): program from Al Jazira television network, interview and retrospective of his work, 1998 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0009)
    - Bacho, Ginane Makki: "Art & Life" [artist video], [spring 1995] (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0038)
    - Choucair, Saloua Raouda: footage of opening of exhibition of her work at Dar al-Nadwa, Beirut, in presence of artist and with remarks from dignitaries, 4 June1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0032)
    - Choucair, Saloua Raouda (filmed in home and studio in Beirut), undated, circa 1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0075)
    - Efflatoun, Inji: documentary film, copy of "Inji," by Mohamed Shaaban (Egypt: National Cinema Center), 1988 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0057)
    - Ftouni, Amal: "Women and Patterns", undated (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0016)
    - Ftouni, Amal. "Amal Ftouni's 'Women and Patterns'" (sent by artist), undated (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0060)
    - Halaby, Samia A.: video documentary, titled "Samia Halaby: an Artist's Personal Promise," directed by David Howard, 1987 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0055)
    - Hassan el-Farouj, Fatima (filmed in Morocco) and Baya [Mahieddine] (filmed in Algeria), with art historian Malika Bouabdallah, July 1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0069)
    - Mosly, Mounirah: interview with unidentified host, undated, circa 1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0017)
    - Sukkarieh, Rabia: unidentified Arabic broadcast, featuring her speaking, November 1992 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0029)
    - Talal, Chaibia (filmed at her home in Morocco), 3 July 1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0068)
    - Three artists (compilation): Ivonne A.-Baki (10 minutes, from Spanish-language televsion program), Samia Halaby (30 minuntes, copy of David Howard documentary), Rabia Sukkarieh (45 minutes, artist's overview of her work), undated (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0056)
    - On location interviews, part 8 of 8: Houria Niati (London), 30 August 1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0018)
    - On location interviews, part 1 of 8: Laila Muraywid (Paris), undated, circa July 1993
    - On location interviews, part 2 of 8: Jumana el-Husseini and Oumana Soubra (Paris), 26 June 1993
    - On location interviews, part 3 of 8: Layla Shawa (London), undated, circa 1993
    - On location interviews, part 4 of 8: Chaibia Talal (Morocco), July 1993
    - On location interviews, part 5 of 8: Fatima Hassan el-Farouj (Morocco), July 1993
    - On location interviews, part 6 of 8: Baya [Mahieddine], with Malika Bouabdallah (Algeria), July 1993
    - On location interviews, part 7 of 8: Saloua Raouda Choucair (Beirut), undated, circa 1993
    - Vosburgh, Carolyn Buck, and Jamal, Ghada: "Point, Line, and the Horizon: a painting installation" (video created by Steven Vosburgh), 1997 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0037)
  - Forces of Change: planning and installation
    - Forces of Change: exhibition opening footage. Includes various artists presenting their work, such as Huguette Caland, Balqees Fakhro, Mounirah Mosly, Liliane Karnouk, and others, as well as comments from exhibition curator Salwa Mikdadi Nashashibi, a poetry reading by Etel Adnan, and a sung performance by Nouria Hiati., 6 February 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0070)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition opening footage. Includes various artists presenting their work, such as Huguette Caland, Balqees Fakhro, Mounirah Mosly, Liliane Karnouk, Mona Saudi, and others, as well as comments from exhibition curator Salwa Mikdadi Nashashibi, a poetry reading by Etel Adnan, and a sung performance by Nouria Hiati., 12 February 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0004)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition opening footage, part 2. Includes song performance by Houria Niati, sculptor Mona Saudi discussing her work, and images of guests in galleries. Second portion of video shows layout of galleries prior to opening, and exterior of museum with banner, 6, 7, and 12 February 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0067)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition walkthrough, Washington, DC. Narrated by Leila Gorchev, with slides at end, February 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0023)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition walkthrough, Washington, DC. Narrated by Leila Gorchev, with slides at end, 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0039)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition walkthrough, Washington, DC (no slides), 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0030)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition walkthrough (with slides at end), 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0031)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition walk through video, with slides and music, narrated by Leila Gorchev. Master copy, 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0064)
    - Forces of Change: exhibition walk through video, with slides and music, narrated by Leila Gorchev, 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0054)
    - Forces of Change: documentary film with artist interviews, narrated by Casey Kasem and Leila Gorchev, edited master, 1 August 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0065)
    - Forces of Change: documentary film with artist interviews, revised with different (uncredited) narrators, 21 August 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0061)
    - ICWA: footage from preview exhibition in Los Angeles of "Forces of Change," as well as televised footage of other artists. Featuring work and interviews with Huguette Caland, Rabia Sukkarieh, Hanaa al-Wardi, Siham Moghraby, at that event, and clips from television interviews with Madiha Umar (Arabic), Ivonee A.-Baki (Spanish), Samia Halaby, undated, circa 1992 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0019)
    - ICWA: footage from preview exhibition in Los Angeles of "Forces of Change," as well as televised footage of other artists. Featuring work and interviews with Huguette Caland, Rabia Sukkarieh, Hanaa al-Wardi, Siham Moghraby, at that event, and clips from television interviews with Madiha Umar (Arabic), Ivonee A.-Baki (Spanish), Samia Halaby, 12 November 1993 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0024)
  - Forces of Change: publicity and events
    - "Around Town," WETA, channel 26 (Washington, DC): feature about "Forces of Change", 17 March 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0001)
    - Salwa Mikdadi Nashashibi: talk at unidentified venue, in Arabic, titled "Al-surah wa al-kitabah bein al-shi'ir wa al-fanan", undated, circa 1997 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0044)
    - Symposium: "Arab Women Reshape Their Reality" (National Museum of Women and the Arts), part 1: Arts and Literature. Featured speakers include, Etel Adnan, Wijdan Ali, with introduction by Salwa Mikdadi Nashashibi., 12 February 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0058)
    - Symposium: "Arab Women Reshape Their Reality" National Museum of Women and the Arts), part 3: Science, Archaeology and Medicine, featuring Nahid Toubia, Salwa Rasmy, and Lamia al-Gailani, 12 February 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0048)
    - Symposium: "Arab Women Reshape Their Reality" (National Museum of Women and the Arts, Washington, DC), part 3: Science, Archaeology and Medicine., 12 February 1994 (Box 1, Object ID: 022.0051)
- Audio